const essentialsChapter16QuizData = [
  {
    id: "16_1",
    question: "Where should you look to find the proper fuel for a gas appliance, assuming it hasn't been converted? (Page 207)",
    options: ["The data plate", "ChatGPT", "Always assume it is natural gas", "Google"],
    answer: "The data plate"
  },
  {
    id: "16_2",
    question: "The data plate will not provide information about the proper clearance requirements for a gas appliance and connector. (Page 207)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False"
  },
  {
    id: "16_3",
    question: "NFPA 54 has language that indicates if the fuel type is changed for a gas appliance, _________. (Page 207)",
    options: ["A label is to be placed on the appliance identifying the new fuel type", "The appliance is no longer usable", "Always assume it is natural gas", "The entire system's venting system needs changed as well"],
    answer: "A label is to be placed on the appliance identifying the new fuel type"
  },
  {
    id: "16_4",
    question: "If an appliance's fuel is switched, the relabeling many not have occurred. (Page 207)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True"
  },
  {
    id: "16_5",
    question: "Category 1 gas appliances that use a combustion fan at the outlet of the heat exchanger are known as a(n) _________. (Page 208)",
    options: ["Fan-Assisted Combustion Appliance", "Outlet Combustion Exchangers", "Air Powered Heaters", "Heat Exchanger Driven Appliances"],
    answer: "Fan-Assisted Combustion Appliance"
  },
  {
    id: "16_6",
    question: "If the data plate is visible, getting the determining the gas appliance's efficiency is part of a Level 1 Inspection. (Page 208)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True"
  },
  {
    id: "16_7",
    question: "The first step for examining an oil appliance is _________. (Page 208)",
    options: ["Look at the data plate", "Make sure it fires up", "Examine the venting system", "Sweep the flue"],
    answer: "Look at the data plate"
  },
  {
    id: "16_8",
    question: "Oil appliance data plates display input rating in either _________, _________ or _________. (Page 208)",
    options: ["BTUs, Gallons Per Hour or Both", "BTUs, Inches of Water Column or Both", "Inches of Water Column, Gallons Per Hour or Liters Per Minute", "BTUs, Oil Per Hour or Gallons Per Hour"],
    answer: "BTUs, Gallons Per Hour or Both"
  },
  {
    id: "16_9",
    question: "An Oil Appliance can sometimes be converted to a Gas Appliance. (Page 208)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True"
  },
  {
    id: "16_10",
    question: "If the data plate cannot be located or is illegible, the clearance for single wall connector for gas units is _________. (Page 208)",
    options: ["6 inches", "18 inches", "9 inches", "2 inches"],
    answer: "6 inches"
  },
  {
    id: "16_11",
    question: "If the data plate cannot be located or is illegible, the clearance for single wall connector for oil units is _________. (Page 208)",
    options: ["6 inches", "18 inches", "9 inches", "2 inches"],
    answer: "18 inches"
  },
  {
    id: "16_12",
    question: "Single Wall Connectors can be used in an attic installation, crawl space or other cold area. (Page 208)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False"
  },
  {
    id: "16_13",
    question: "B-Vent is considered a(n) _________ connector. (Page 208)",
    options: ["Insulated", "Zero-Clearance", "Dangerous", "Wood Burning Appliance"],
    answer: "Insulated"
  },
  {
    id: "16_14",
    question: "L-Vent is considered a(n) _________ connector. (Page 208)",
    options: ["Insulated", "Zero-Clearance", "Dangerous", "Wood Burning Appliance"],
    answer: "Insulated"
  },
  {
    id: "16_15",
    question: "Connector pipes should not be longer _________ of the height of the vent. (Page 208)",
    options: ["75%", "25%", "90%", "125%"],
    answer: "75%"
  },
  {
    id: "16_16",
    question: "You are sweeping and inspecting a Gas or Oil Appliance. You need to make sure the rise of the connector pipe (if there is one) is correct. What should it be at minimum? (Page 208)",
    options: ["1/4 inch per foot", "1/4 foot per inch", "1/4 inch per inch", "1 foot per 3 feet"],
    answer: "1/4 inch per foot"
  },
  {
    id: "16_17",
    question: "You are inspecting a gas or oil unit's venting system and notice corrosion of the flue resulting in spalling or flaking. What is this most likely from? (Page 209)",
    options: ["Condensation that contains acidic residues", "Chimney Fire", "Burning Wood in these units", "Animal Intrusion"],
    answer: "Condensation that contains acidic residues"
  },
  {
    id: "16_18",
    question: "If a chimney doesn't extend more than 12 inches below the entrance of the connector, what could happen? (Page 209)",
    options: ["It could become blocked more quickly at that area", "Flow increases", "Draft increases", "A Downdraft happens"],
    answer: "It could become blocked more quickly at that area"
  },
  {
    id: "16_19",
    question: "Gas or oil appliances can be vented into the same flue that serves a solid fuel appliance. (Page 209)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False"
  },
  {
    id: "16_20",
    question: "Before sweeping an oil or gas appliance, you should verify it fires. (Page 210)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True"
  },
  {
    id: "16_21",
    question: "Before powering down an oil or gas appliance, you should verify the appliance _________ and _________ work. (Page 210)",
    options: ["Thermostat and Power Switch", "Door and Handle", "Flux Capacitor and Reactor", "Controller and Gas Supply"],
    answer: "Thermostat and Power Switch"
  },
  {
    id: "16_22",
    question: "A common method for powering down oil burning appliances is to shut off the emergency switch. (Page 210)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True"
  },
  {
    id: "16_23",
    question: "Shut of gas appliances with a pilot by turning the gas selector switch to the _________ position. (Page 210)",
    options: ["Pilot", "Off", "On"],
    answer: "Pilot"
  },
  {
    id: "16_24",
    question: "If sweeping the flue of a gas appliance, it is alright for the homeowner, or anyone else, to readjust the thermostat. (Page 210)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False"
  },
  {
    id: "16_25",
    question: "If soot from oil appliances fall, how should you pick it up? (Page 211)",
    options: ["Use a vacuum and hover over it. Do not touch it.", "Wipe it with your hand", "Drag your vacuum hose directly on the soot", "Smear it with your foot"],
    answer: "Use a vacuum and hover over it. Do not touch it."
  },
  {
    id: "16_26",
    question: "What is one reason why you should wear a respirator while sweeping oil flues. (Page 211)",
    options: ["The soot and fumes combine with moisture to produce Sulfuric Acid, which could render you breathless", "You can instantly die", "Arsenic compounds can cause de-pigmentation of the skin", "They always contain histoplasmosis"],
    answer: "The soot and fumes combine with moisture to produce Sulfuric Acid, which could render you breathless"
  },
  {
    id: "16_27",
    question: "Connectors should be joined and secured with 2 screws. (Page 211)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False"
  },
  {
    id: "16_28",
    question: "Draft is measured in _________. (Page 212)",
    options: ["Inches of Water Column", "Miles Per Hour", "BTUs", "Feet Per Second"],
    answer: "Inches of Water Column"
  },
  {
    id: "16_29",
    question: "1 inch of water column is the pressure difference required to lift a column of water _________ up a tube. (Page 212)",
    options: ["1 inch", "2 inches", "3 inches", "1.5 inches"],
    answer: "1 inch"
  },
  {
    id: "16_30",
    question: "Draft is checked in 2 places _________ and _________. (Page 212)",
    options: ["Above the fire and 6 inches from the appliance flue outlet", "Above the fire and at the top of the chimney", "At the bottom of the chimney and at the top of the chimney", "5 inches from the appliance flue outlet and 10 inches from the appliance flue outlet"],
    answer: "Above the fire and 6 inches from the appliance flue outlet"
  },
  {
    id: "16_31",
    question: "Room temperature air enters through the barometric draft control in the precise amount needed to overcome excess drafts. (Page 212)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True"
  },
  {
    id: "16_32",
    question: "To reset a stack control unit, you should pull the lever on the rod out slowly about 1/4 inch and then release it slowly. (Page 213)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True"
  },
  {
    id: "16_33",
    question: "Every time you sweep a chimney a _________ is required. (Page 214)",
    options: ["Level I", "Level II", "Level III", "Category II"],
    answer: "Level I"
  },
  {
    id: "16_34",
    question: "According to the NFPA 211, chimney and venting systems should be inspected once a year and swept when necessary. (Page 214)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True"
  },
  {
    id: "16_35",
    question: "After you share the report with the homeowner, if possible have them _________. (Page 214)",
    options: ["Sign the report", "Shake your hand", "Only verbally acknowledge the report", "Prove they know how to use their fireplace"],
    answer: "Sign the report"
  },
];


if (!window.quizRegistry) window.quizRegistry = {};
window.quizRegistry['Chapter 16: Sweeping Gas and Oil Appliance Chimneys or Vents'] = essentialsChapter16QuizData;
